Vy Vannak

- Coding Teacher
- Full Stack Developer
- IT Support
- Electrician



PREAH DAK, BANTEAY SREY, SIEM REAP, CAMBODIA (081) 33 61 31 vannakvy2020@gmail.com

Why do I want to join your amazing team?

I see this opportunity as a way to contribute to an exciting, forward-thinking and fast-moving team, and I feel I can do so with my experiences and my passion. Plus I am doing my master degree that contains data science and machine learning so that hopefully this will make me suitable for the job.

EXPERIENCES

CHAMPION CODER, Siem Reap — Coding Teacher

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Working for this company as a part-time job, and then currently as a full-time job. My jobs are to teach computer programming to children as well as writing curriculum to fit students' ages and levels. I am right now teaching Web development, Python, Thunkable (Block based Mobile app building platform), and Basic Robotic.

GOGLOBAL SCHOOL, Siem Reap — IT Manager

2021 - 2022

I got promoted as an IT Manager. My roles were to lead three main departments such as IT Networking, Software development and Design.

GOGLOBAL SCHOOL, Siem Reap — Full Stack Developer

2020 - 2021

I work as a software developer. My role is to design and develop softwares as required by the company.

SOKHA SIEM REAP HOTEL AND CONVENTION CENTER, Siem Reap — *IT OFFICER*

MAY 2018 - 2021

I was working in Sokha Siem Reap Hotel and Convention center as an IT Officer, and My roles are to control, manage, and support Wifi , Server, Network , software ,POS, Cable TV , IPTV and Cameras.

SKILLS

☑ Coding Mentor

✓ Electrical

☑ IT Support

☑ Software Developer

AWARDS

I got a prize as a top scorer in my English courses in Pannasastra University

I got 5.0 of IELTS test in 2014 just after learning English for a year

Best Employee of the month and the Year. After working at Sokha Hotel for a year I was nominated as the best Employee of the month and then the Best Employee of the Year.

Number one on class provided by the Hotel, English for Hospitality and catering

The prize of creating lighting control system using blue microcontrollers with c++ programming

SOKHA SIEM REAP HOTEL AND CONVENTION CENTER Siem Reap — *ELECTRICIAN*

JULY 2017 - 2018

Before I started working as an IT Officer, I worked as an Electrician and my roles were maintenance electrical systems in the room, leading a team and installing electrical stuff.

HVC, SIEM REAP — ENGLISH TEACHER

MONTH 2013 - MONTH 2014

When I just finished my High school, I got a scholarship from an NGO, so I spent more than a year mastering my English in Pannasastra University. In the meantime, through the NGO, I had a chance to teach children English in another NGO called Honor Village of Cambodia (HVC). I learned and taught at the same time so that I was able to improve my English faster.

SECURITY GUARD, SIEM REAP — SECURITY GUARD

2010 - 2011

My Life is taught as an orphanage, I lost my mother when I was 3 and 11 years later my father passed away. I had to live on my own. To get by I decided to work at night as a Security Guard In Siem Reap City and went to my high school by day.

EDUCATION

BUILD BRIGHT UNIVERSITY, PHNOM PENH — *MIT*

JULY 2023 - PRESENT

As I am conscious about technology and programming, I started doing a degree in Information Technology at the University of South-East Asia, and I am currently in my final year.

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH-EAST ASIA, SIEM REAP — BA

JULY 2017 - 2022

As I am conscious about technology and programming, I started doing a degree in Information Technology at the University of South-East Asia, and I am currently in my final year.

LANGUAGES

| GOOD | FAIR |
|-----------|-----------|
| | \otimes |
| \otimes | |
| | \otimes |
| | GOOD 🥥 |

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

| ⊘ css |
|----------------------|
| ⊘ JAVASCRIPT |
| ⊘ PYTHON |
| ⊘ C++ |
| ⊘ JAVA |
| ⊘ TYPESCRIPT |
| ⊘ Micropython |
| Scratch |

HOBBIES



SOCIAL WORKS

Join project B
Fixing bike for children

SANGKHA INDUSTRIAL AND COMMUNICATION COLLEGE, THAILAND — BA

MAY 2014 - JANUARY 2017

Right After I had done the course (Intensive English for Academic Purpose) at Pannasastra University. I got an opportunity to study in Thailand in one of the Thai Government Colleges. It is a Vocational College to prepare and offer students skills. I chose electrical engineering, and spent 8 hours a day and 5 days a week learning. I had to speak Thai in the class so I had to challenge myself to learn Thai. I did it so now I can speak and write some Thai. I did complete the course for 2 and a half years.

PANNASASTRA UNIVERSITY, SIEM REAP — ENGLISH

MATCH 2013 - APRIL 2014

I got a scholarship from a NGO called Cambodia Rural Student Trust, so that I was able to go to a University to master my English. I spent more than a year studying for my IEAP at Pannasastra University.

10 JANUARY HIGH SCHOOL, SIEM REAP— HIGH SCHOOL

2012 - 2013

After my Grade 11, I left my hometown, Banteay Srey, for the city for my Grade 12 class at 10 January High School.

BANTEAY SREY HIGH SCHOOL, SIEM REAP— HIGH SCHOOL & SECONDARY SCHOOL

2007 - 2012

I spent almost all of my Secondary and High School in Banteay Srey High School. I dropped out for two years because of poverty and the loss of my father and mother. It was really tough for me as my mother passed away when I was 3 years old and then lost my father at the age of 14. Then I realized that only education can change and make my life better so I went to school again.

PREAH DAK PRIMARY SCHOOL, SIEM REAP— *PRIMARY SCHOOL*

2000 - 2007

Preah Dak Primary School is where I started my academy journey as it is the closest and the only one primary school in my commune.

PROJECTS



PROJECTS TWO

SMART HOME controlling Home appliances using smart phones using Bluetooth

This is my very first project with programming. I was when I was studying in Thailand.

SMART HOME — Controlling electrical devices using ESP8266, Raspberry Pi, Web Interface and MQTT protocol.

It is a bigger project as it was an IoT project. It required a Raspberry Pi board to run two different servers , MQTT Broker (a subscribe and publish messaging protocol) and Node-red (a web interface for making UI on the web and connecting the logic). Moreover, I also used ESP8266 to subscribe, publish messages and relays so that I can control 220v devices.

ROBOT CAR —Car Robot using Adafruit motor driver, bluetooth, arduino uno and smart phone.

It was a robot car controlled by a smartphone via bluetooth.

COVID-19 TRACKER — TRACKING COVID-19 NUMBER OF CASES

While I was working as an IT Support, I had created a website that can be used to display in the lobby of the hotel. It showed cases of covid-19 in Cambodia, Asean and some other major countries around the world.

COVID-19 SYSTEM — FOR SIEM REAP GOVERNMENT

During the covid pandemic the compare I was working for has a close relation with Siem Reap Governor, so we built a system for keeping track of the tested patients , positive and negative , and also hospitalize patients. All of my team who are involved in this project are from the USEA, we work hard day and night to make sure we finish in time.

SCRATCH CURRICULUM — SCRATCH PROGRAMMING

I have been designing a curriculum that can be used for students in Siem Reap, in a school I am working for. This is the course that we need to introduce programming to students who are new to programming, especially children.

HTML & CSS CURRICULUM — WEB DEVELOPMENT

As a teacher teaching coding in Siem Reap, I am assigned to design the curriculum that can be used to teach children web development. Actually we already have an existing curriculum but it is not quite effective enough with students here so I have to recreate a new one that is more effective and fits the students here. I already finished designing HTML and CSS and right now working on Javascript.

JAVASCRIPT LANGUAGE — JAVASCRIPT

This is the curriculum that I have been working on as students who are studenting on HTML and CSS are about to finish. This Javascript course is mainly focusing on DOM Manipulation. It means this course will teach students to run Javascript on the browsers to make websites interactive.

BBC:Microbit with Scratch —BBC: MICROBIT + SCRATCH

Designing Scratch curriculum that can be used to connect and control BBC: Microbit Board.

CONTROLLING MOTORS AND SENSOR — Working with arduino board and sensors.

I spent time experimenting with other arduino boards such as Arduino Nano, Mega, Uno. I also learnt about sensors like LDR, Ultra, Bluetooth, and so on. More than that I am able to work with motors both DC and AC, Stepper Motor and Server.

USING BBC:MICRO BIT BOARD — Get it up and running using different Languages, micropython, javascript and c++.

Several months ago I started interested in Python and Micropython, I then did some research and found a BBC: Microbit board that can be compiled in more than one language . I bought it and got it up and running . Personally, I think it is super great for teaching children to code using it.